现代电动机是很好的设备，但它们的性能有限。
Modern electric motors are wonderful devices, but there are limits to their performance.
有最大加速度，最大速度和最大功率。
There is a maximum acceleration, a maximum velocity and a maximum power.
那么，让我们首先看一下限制电机加速度的因素。我们已经重新安排了
So, let’s look first at what limits the acceleration of a motor. We have rearranged
此处此形式的早期等式，电机转矩与电机的比率
an earlier equation in to this form here, the ratio of the motor torque to the motor
惯性。很明显，因为惯性在分母中，如果我们增加惯性，我们就是
inertia. Clearly because inertia is in the denominator, if we increase inertia, we are
要减少加速度。电机经受的惯性有两个组成部分。
going to reduce the acceleration. The inertia that the motor experiences has got two components.
其中一个组件是电机电枢的惯性。那是旋转的
One of those components is the inertia of the motor’s armature. That’s the rotating
我用Jsubm表示的电动机的一部分。电机经历的另一个惯性
part of electric motor that I denote by J sub m. The other inertia that the motor experiences
是由于链接本身。在这种情况下，我绘制了一个非常简单的矩形
is due to the link itself. In this case, I have drawn a very simple rectangular
链接的棱镜和惯性是M倍R平方。R平方是有问题的
prism for the link and the inertia of that is M times R squared. The R squared is problematic
因为它意味着惯性随着链接的大小而迅速增长。
because it means that the inertia grows very quickly with the size of the link.
因此，我们可以根据这两个组成部分编写电机所经历的总惯性，
So, we can write the total inertia that the motor experiences in terms of these two components,
电动机电枢惯性是一个常数和链路的惯性。而且，在这
the motor armature inertia which is a constant and the inertia of the link. And, in this
简单的情况下，链接的惯性是一个常数。但是，对于真正的机器人来说，惯性
simple case, the inertia of the link is a constant. But, for a real robot, the inertia
将取决于附加到末尾的所有链接的配置
is going to depend on the configuration of all the links that are attached to the end
这个特定链接以及链中最后一个链接所持有的有效载荷。
of this particular link and also to the payload which is held by the last link in the chain.
因此，链路惯性将变化很大。然而，在真正的机器人中，有
So, the link inertia is going to be highly variable. However, in a real robot, there's
通常是电机和链路之间的变速箱，这是另一个优点
typically a gearbox between the motor and the link and this is another advantage of
变速箱因为它允许我像这样写惯性表达式。
the gearbox because it allows me to write the expression for inertia like this.
链路的惯性减小了G平方因子。而且，对于像Puma这样的机器人，
The inertia of the link is reduced by a factor of G squared. And, for a robot like the Puma,
G是一个介于10和100之间的数字。因此，链接惯性将是
G is a number anywhere between say 10 and a 100. So, the link inertia is going to be
大大减少了。这意味着电机控制系统的惯性
greatly reduced. It means that the inertia that the motor control system is going to
“看”是由恒定的电动机电枢惯性决定的。
“see” is dominated by the constant motor armature inertia.
由链路配置变化引起的惯性变化将非常非常小。如果
Variation in inertia due to link configuration change is going to be very, very small. If
我们现在考虑表达式顶部的分子，我们知道最大扭矩
we consider now the numerator of the expression at the top, we know that the maximum torque
取决于最大电流。最大可能电流是功率的函数
depends on the maximum current. The maximum possible current is a function of the power
为电动机提供电流的放大器。如果我们给电机施加太多电流，
amplifier which supplies current to the motor. If we apply too much current to the motor,
电枢和电刷会过热而损坏。
the armature and the brushes will overheat and be damaged.
另外，请记住，电机产生的一些扭矩用于抵抗摩擦和
Also, remember that some of the torque generated by the motor is used to oppose friction and
也反对电机的重力。因此，实际上可用于加速的较少。
also to oppose gravity in the motor. So, less of it is actually available for acceleration.
我们在这里定义的是机器人关节最大加速度的上限。
What we have defined here is an upper bound on the maximum acceleration of the robot joint.
现在转到电机的电气模型所包含的最大速度
Turning now to the maximum velocity the electrical model for the motor contains
一个发电机，圆圈是反电动势源，随着电机旋转越来越快，
a generator, the circle is the back EMF source, and as the motor rotates faster and faster, the
反电动势上升。并且，当反电动势等于施加的电压时，则不再有电流
back EMF rises. And, when the back EMF equals the applied voltage, then no further current
可以流入电机。它将停止加速，并将定义最大速度
can flow in to motor. It will stop accelerating and that will define the maximum speed of
由这样的等式给出的电动机。给出了电动机的电功率
the motor given by an equation like this. The electrical power in to the motor is given
通过施加的电压和电流的乘积。电机的机械功率
by the product of the applied voltage and current. The mechanical power out of the motor
是速度和扭矩的产物。我们可以根据电机速度绘制电机扭矩
is the product of speed and the torque. We can plot motor torque against motor speed
此曲线还有其他两个关键点。
and there are other two critical points on this curve.
有一点是电机完全没有负载并且它的旋转速度尽可能快
One point is when the motor has got no load at all and it’s spinning as fast as it possibly
能够。我们称之为空载速度。在线的另一端，电机是
can. We refer to this as the no load speed. At the other end of the line, the motor is
停滞不前。它实际上不是在旋转，而是在施加扭矩，我们参考这个
stalled. It’s not actually rotating but it is exerting a torque and we refer to this
作为失速扭矩。功率是速度的二次函数
as the stall torque. Power is a quadratic function of speed has
最大值在电机运行速度范围的中间位置，电机不能
a maximum somewhere in the middle of the operating speed range of the motor and the motor cannot
操作一段时间超过其最大额定功率，否则它
be operated for a sustained period of time above its maximum power rating or else it
会因过热而损坏。
will be damaged through overheating.